<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Pomodori</title>
 <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/"/>
 <updated>2009-10-20T07:35:08-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Reborg</name>
   <email>reborg@reborg.net</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>View History Feature</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/06/08/historyview.html"/>
   <updated>2009-06-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/06/08/historyview</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id='release_03_is_close'&gt;Release 0.3 is close!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;#8217;m almost ready to release again Pomodori after the introduction of the history view. Basically pomodoro counts are now clickable and a table shows up with timestamps and descriptions for yesterday&amp;#8217;s or today&amp;#8217;s pomodoros worked. The table is useful to see at the beginning of the day what was done yesterday very quickly. Try it at your next stan-up meeting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also important performance improvements, UI tweaks and internal architectural changes. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='700_pomodoros'&gt;700+ pomodoros&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m happy to see the pomodoro count increasing so fast. The more data are stored in Pomodori the more I can inspect about my practice and improve. Cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Happy pomodoros to all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fixed performance issue</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/05/12/perfomances.html"/>
   <updated>2009-05-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/05/12/perfomances</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id='well_over_400_pomodoros'&gt;Well over 400 Pomodoros&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started noticing an increasing delay during the use of the Pomodori tool since some weeks ago. I easily correlated the problem to the increasing number of pomodoros in my pomodoro database. Right now I have around 450 entries in the table and every time I started Pomodori, or simply switching between running/break status resulted in this annoying 2 secs refresh of the user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to investigate and I found to major problems: first, I was calling the computation of the average twice by mistake and second, even removing the double call, find all pomodoros was really slow. I had a look at the Kirbybase manual to see what I was doing wrong and there is a very nicely done &lt;a href='http://www.netpromi.com/files/kirbybase_ruby_manual.html#tips-on-improving-performance' title='Perf section'&gt;performance section there&lt;/a&gt; that says &amp;#8220;Beware of Date/DateTime&amp;#8221;. Of course I was using Time as the database type for pomodoros timestamps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I migrated the type of the column to string and modified the rest of the application to deal with string comparisons for date related queries. I created a &lt;a href='http://github.com/reborg/pomodori/blob/master/lib/pomodori/extensions/timestamp.rb' title='String Extension'&gt;string extension&lt;/a&gt; to deal with timestamps. The problem then was how to migrate the already existing database file (pomodoro.tbl) to the new column type. I extracted the migration portion from KirbyStorage into a new &lt;a href='http://github.com/reborg/pomodori/blob/master/lib/pomodori/migration.rb' title='Migration Class'&gt;migration class&lt;/a&gt; where I check at startup if the database should be migrated. So if you are using Pomodori already you shouldn&amp;#8217;t be worried to trash your old pomodoro history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#8217;m happy to have back my nice and fluid Pomodori interface. By the way numbers for the find all went down from 1.4s to 0.14s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='new_features'&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several other important things I&amp;#8217;m working on right now. I&amp;#8217;m going to open a window if you click on the yesterday&amp;#8217;s count to show you the related Pomodoros. The pomodoro/count/day that now is a separate chart will be integrated in the main window to give you a quick overview of your performance in the last 30 days. I&amp;#8217;m also working on a secret feature&amp;#8230;. don&amp;#8217;t tell anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Happy pomodoros to all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>history table view</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/16/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-04-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/16/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='session_planned_8'&gt;SESSION PLANNED 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='session_done_8'&gt;SESSION DONE 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@planning 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori \@tiny need to go through the gh-pages process once again because I lost connection with real site 1 =&amp;gt; 0&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori \@yestpomo spike scrollable grid-table views 2 =&amp;gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori \@yestpomo history view with grid table view showing list of pomodoros 4 =&amp;gt; 4&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@pomospective 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='session_not_done'&gt;SESSION NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yesterday I did some UI work to compact the view and some design for the yestpomo story&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Today I&amp;#8217;d like to close the full yesterday&amp;#8217;s pomo story&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Today: strictly observe breaks(!) Next email check during long break. Full stop!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='pomospective'&gt;POMOSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can do better for my 4 pomos longer breaks. Do I really really have to read the email? Should I start scheduling a working pomo for that instead? The reason is: reading emails/tweets is brain consuming.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I thought allocating only 8 when I see a potential of 11-12 was not enough. But I had my 2 longer breaks (12-2) plus sometimes I don&amp;#8217;t stop right away after the 25 mins and I do another 5 (12-2-1) and I started allocating for the pomospective (12-2-1-1)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;So if you see a potential of 12 allocate a (-3) 9. If you see a 16 (a full day) allocate for a 12 (-4).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I underestimated the lenght of the history story. So today I&amp;#8217;m not done. The problem is that I need to spend more time than expected for things like the table view to understand how the work.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Next time, for a full story, allocate more than the impression of what needs to be done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='interruptions'&gt;INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  177|\@planning|2009-04-16 07:32:31 -0500
  178|\@pomodori \@yestpomo spiking on table view got the whole picture, understanding details.|2009-04-16 08:03:44 -0500
  179|\@pomodori \@yestpomo learned about the complicated problem of resizeable cells in a table view|2009-04-16 08:36:33 -0500
  180|\@pomodori \@yestpomo created history view. Was thinking about poor man line soft wrapping.|2009-04-16 09:07:22 -0500
  181|\@pomodori \@yestpomo evaluating effort for soft-wrapping on 3 lines of text|2009-04-16 10:04:14 -0500
  182|\@pomodori \@yestpomo written a method for softwrapping to a given lenght|2009-04-16 10:35:12 -0500
  183|\@pomodori \@yestpomo created hashify for pomodoro|2009-04-16 11:06:00 -0500
  184|\@pomodori \@yestpomo added the table view and the main window to the history view|2009-04-16 11:37:57 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>making space on the main view</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/15/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-04-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/15/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='session_planned_7'&gt;SESSION PLANNED 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='session_done_5'&gt;SESSION DONE 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@planning 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori instead of the label &amp;#8220;running&amp;#8221; in the summary, try to change the title bar instead 1 =&amp;gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori \@refactoring KirbyStorage contains methods like yesterday or today pomodoros. I think they should go into pomodori controller to call relevant methods from kirby storage. 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori \@yestpomo spike on different kind of windows and retrieve mouse position 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='session_not_done'&gt;SESSION NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori \@yestpomo spike scrollable grid-table views 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;d like to work on the pomo history to display the dump of raw pomodoros (first step) instead of opening the file by hand to copy the raw dump&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Still not sure how to handle the new window in the UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='pomospective'&gt;POMOSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did a big underestimation and I grabbed the next task&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I was tired at the end I skipped one pomo&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Distractions are more tempting when I&amp;#8217;m tired. Doh.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I always have the feeling I&amp;#8217;ve done something thanks to pomos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='interruptions'&gt;INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@internal as usual, reading blogs I couldn&amp;#8217;t resist to read some more. Damn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  172|\@planning|2009-04-15 17:08:58 -0500
  173|\@pomodori \@yestpomo want to update the main title on running modes, but this breaks the tests!|2009-04-15 17:40:14 -0500
  174|\@pomodori change title bar working now with new compacted layout. Had to remove the running mode call from main view init|2009-04-15 18:11:56 -0500
  175|\@pomodori \@refactoring moved two unrelated methods from kirby to pomo controller|2009-04-15 18:42:49 -0500
  176|\@pomodori \@yestpomo started analyizing the problem of catching mouse position|2009-04-15 19:20:54 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>average pomodoros and specs</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/14/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-04-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/14/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='session_planned_7'&gt;SESSION PLANNED 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@pomodoro \@history instead of the label &amp;#8220;running&amp;#8221; in the summary, try to change the title bar instead 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori \@refactoring KirbyStorage contains methods like yesterday or today pomodoros. I think they should go into pomodori controller to call relevant methods from kirby storage. 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='session_done_5'&gt;SESSION DONE 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori \@planning 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori \@setup Matchy http://github.com/jeremymcanally/matchy is another rspec like syntax for test::unit 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori \@setup I&amp;#8217;d like to use this microspec.rb 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@pomodori \@metrics add average pomodoros per day in the summary 2 =&amp;gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='session_not_done'&gt;SESSION NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last session I was able to close release 0.2&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Today I need to finish ChiRb slides for tonight&amp;#8217;s talk&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Planning on a 2 pomodoros presentation&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll leave the last part for the train tonight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='pomospective'&gt;POMOSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short breaks, I felt the pressure of closing the slides with the time available&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Too bad, but I got the slides done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='interruptions'&gt;INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@external starbucks full of smoke and noisy, had to move to caribou&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@internal lost replying tweets, sigh. Voided, lost 5 mins and relaxing during the break! Damn all the free wifi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  167|\@planning|2009-04-14 17:05:55 -0500
  168|\@pomodori \@setup installed matchy and moved mocha into vendor folder|2009-04-14 17:56:52 -0500
  169|\@pomodori \@setup installed microspec ready to use it. Describe blocks doesn't work though.|2009-04-14 18:33:39 -0500
  170|\@pomodori \@metrics adding average on pomodoro controller|2009-04-14 19:04:04 -0500
  171|\@pomodori \@metrics done, daily average integrated|2009-04-14 19:35:46 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>chirb talk</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/06/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-04-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/06/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is both an announce and the planning for today. The announce is that tonight I&amp;#8217;m gonna talk about Pomodori and HotCocoa development at the Chicago Ruby User Group @ ThoughtWorks. Kind of late announce here on the Pomodori&amp;#8217;s blog, but anyway, step by if you have a chance, show permitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='session_planned_8'&gt;SESSION PLANNED 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='session_done_7'&gt;SESSION DONE 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@chirb presentation part 1, macruby, hotcocoa, pomo intro 2 =&amp;gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@chirb presentation part 2, pomodori app, testing challenge, architecture 4 =&amp;gt; 4&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@chirb presentation part 2, conclusions, pros, cons, links 2 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='session_not_done'&gt;SESSION NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last session I was able to close release 0.2&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Today I need to finish ChiRb slides for tonight&amp;#8217;s talk&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Planning on a 2 pomodoros presentation&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll leave the last part for the train tonight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='pomospective'&gt;POMOSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short breaks, I felt the pressure of closing the slides with the time available&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Too bad, but I got the slides done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  145|\@chirb adding code examples on macruby and hotcocoa part|2009-04-06 08:01:30 -0500
  146|\@chirb should be done with macruby hotcocoa and PT intro presentation first part (1 pomo talk time)|2009-04-06 08:33:57 -0500
  147|\@chirb created first Pomodori TDD slides|2009-04-06 09:04:19 -0500
  148|\@chirb drawing architecture slide|2009-04-06 09:36:23 -0500
  149|\@chirb done with main architectural slides|2009-04-06 10:07:18 -0500
  150|\@chirb writing conclusions to close|2009-04-06 10:40:02 -0500
  151|\@chirb done|2009-04-06 11:10:14 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Announcing 0.2 release</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/04/ann-0.2.html"/>
   <updated>2009-04-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/04/ann-0.2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id='pomodori_02_is_out'&gt;Pomodori 0.2 is out!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='../../../resources/chart-pom-count.png' alt='Pomodoro Count' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pomodori now draws charts! The first simple chart has been introduced with this release. The bar chart shows how many pomodoros you worked by day. This metric can be used to see the fluctuation of your productivity over time and why there are good and bad days. This is just the first of a series of chart I&amp;#8217;d like to introduce to improve your Pomodoro Technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I learn to be a better Cocoa programmer, I tweak the UI to be more usable and better looking. I added the pomodoro icon and a gradient to the interface. More substantial UI improvement to come in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A less evident change was done with a huge refactoring to the core classes of Pomodori. There is now an architectural view that I like. As part of the refactoring there is less code which is more simple with more functionalities. The bloated application.rb class has gone and now the view only contains view logic. Multiple controllers have been created to handle all the workflow logic and comunication with the model. Happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next 0.3 release I&amp;#8217;d like to have all the tag based features working, including a chart by tags of pomodoros. Feel free to help me improving Pomodori!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See ya.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>clean-up charts for 0.2</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/03/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-04-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/04/03/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_9'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done_7'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@planning 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@charts The chart-controller is called by the view to obtain the chart url or reload/close operations and the alike 2 =&amp;gt; 2 (Missing: reload button should reload and open report from the main view should always work)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@marketing \@website better screenshot for the website, blog post about 0.2, update documentation release 0.2 1 =&amp;gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@chirb presentation part one, macruby, hotcocoa intro 2 =&amp;gt; 3 (TBD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@chirb presentation part one, macruby, hotcocoa intro 2 =&amp;gt; 3 (TBD)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@chirb presentation part two, pomodoro technique intro 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@chirb presentation part three, pomodori app, testing challenge, architecture 2&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@chirb presentation part four, conclusions, pros, cons, links 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;today should be able to close release 0.2 with the simple chart working properly.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;There is a fix to be done in the way the chart is loaded everytime&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The reload button is not working now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='pomospective'&gt;POMOSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I thought I could close the day later, I had to close it before the exp. time&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;So estimates are right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found interesting examples of MacRuby apps, I couldn&amp;#8217;t resist to have a look.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  137|\@planning|2009-04-03 14:30:20 -0500
  138|\@charts fixed the button behaviors for reload and reopen|2009-04-03 15:01:04 -0500
  139|\@marketing preparing for release 0.2|2009-04-03 15:38:57 -0500
  140|\@marketing re-done screenshots, update blog and home page created zipped app|2009-04-03 16:05:07 -0500
  141|\@chirb created git repo starting writing slides.|2009-04-03 16:35:30 -0500
  142|\@chirb wasted some time for a nice looking ruby image|2009-04-03 17:18:51 -0500
  143|\@chirb wrote first introductory slides|2009-04-03 17:44:30 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>summary chart</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/31/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/31/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_5'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done_6'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@planning planned the plan 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@charts need to tweak the HTML produced 1 =&amp;gt; 3&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@charts The chart-controller is called by the view to obtain the chart url or reload/close operations and the alike 2 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@build commit, test, build automation just a bit 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@charts The chart-controller is called by the view to obtain the chart url or reload/close operations and the alike 2 =&amp;gt; 1 (Missing: reload button should reload and open report from the main view should always work)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@marketing \@website better screenshot for the website, release 0.2 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was almost done with chart processing last session&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Today closing summary chart basics and probably there will be some tweaking next days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='pomospective'&gt;POMOSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Couldn&amp;#8217;t break very well today, feel the pressure of the incoming presentations and the fact that I don&amp;#8217;t know how much time I have available per day these days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  122
\@planning
2009-03-31 14:34:18 -0500
  123
\@charts implemented process method for template but test failing.
2009-03-31 15:05:28 -0500
  124
\@charts I was missing the template in the right place and the main view now needs to start the chart view using the controller
2009-03-31 15:36:31 -0500
  125
\@charts having troubles with the html. CSS seems to be gone.
2009-03-31 16:07:59 -0500
  126
\@charts found the bug right at the end. The css file was not in the tmp directory
2009-03-31 16:41:04 -0500
  127
\@charts fixed UI and main commit. Several other details remain, reload button and reopening view.
2009-03-31 17:13:20 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>template processing</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/29/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/29/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_6'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done_4'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@charts chart model to complete with actual processing of template 1 =&amp;gt; 1 (not finished yet)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@charts Need to finish the pomodoro by count model by returning a collection of pomodoro-by-count models 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@charts Need to add attributes to pomodoro-by-count model to hold relevant data 1 =&amp;gt; 0&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@charts Need to change chart-view to use new chart controller to create URL 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@charts chart model to complete with actual processing of template 1 =&amp;gt; 1 (not finished yet)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@marketing @website better screenshot for the website, formatting of raw dump section in the blog 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@charts The chart-controller is called by the view to obtain the chart url or reload/close operations and the alike 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panera session, noisy but doable.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Should be able to close charting today, only details are missing but the design is down&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I envisioned a collaboration between the view asking to open an URL which is generated by a chart component.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The chart component uses an aggregated pomodoro count by day model object&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I need a chart controller I don&amp;#8217;t want the view to know anything about URL generation logic. Just a plain call.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='pomospective'&gt;POMOSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I just assumed I had 6 pomodoros available but those were really only 5&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Worked very well on breaks, I looked out the window, that&amp;#8217;s it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; 
  119
\@charts done with the chart controller to upload the view with a new url when called
2009-03-29 10:38:43 -0500
  120
\@charts changed the chart view to initialize the page on rendering which is done by the controller
2009-03-29 11:09:37 -0500
  121
\@charts creating html for the summary to complete the chart model
2009-03-29 11:42:13 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>charts in progress</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/27/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/27/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_7'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done_6'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@template a component that reads an html and replaces placeholder with actual data 6 =&amp;gt; 6 (but not finished)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@template a component that reads an html and replaces placeholder with actual data 6 =&amp;gt; 6 (not done)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@charts @layout move back to absolute positioning 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yesterday I did some working on the HTML template prototype and decided that a simple text expansion is all I need&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Today I&amp;#8217;m going to create that component that handle all the html creation from the template to the temp file with real data substitution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='pomospective'&gt;POMOSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fairly good estimates&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Was not able to split the task into subtasks. There are 3 subtasks to this &amp;#8220;component&amp;#8221;. A design pomodoro maybe would do the trick.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several micro-internal-interruptions mainly due to my breaks reading mail and tweets and following up to them on the go. Got to stop this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had an abort session before I closed the last pomodoro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  112|\@charts writing the chart model that loads template and makes substitutions|2009-03-27 07:47:55 -0500
  113|\@charts creating logic to replace a ERB like tag from a line of text|2009-03-27 08:18:38 -0500
  114|\@charts going strategies from the main chart class to create different types of charts. The summary is the default, by day is the second.|2009-03-27 08:51:21 -0500
  115|\@charts done with the template processing, only need to call pomodorocountbyday|2009-03-27 09:23:52 -0500
  116|\@charts implementing the pomodoro by count class. Creating the test pomodoros.|2009-03-27 10:20:11 -0500
  117|\@charts almost done with the pomo count abstraction. Need to create attr accessors.|2009-03-27 10:51:31 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>back to charts</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/26/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/26/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_4'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done_3'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\@spike samr try to use it for an html file defining a syntax similar to erb. 4 =&amp;gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;\@spike custom solution to the html parsing problem 2 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closed all refactoring operations. The architecture is now: 1 class to handle the UI for a window, multiple controllers to handle widget on that window, models if persisted state is involved.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Also tweaked the UI using a nice looking gradient fill.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Today: back to business value! I left charting when I created that mocked view to show the web-view and css-charting was a working possibility&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I need a template mechanism with placeholders for the chart template. Radius was not parsing correctly. Placeholder by hand are good until I need looping. Samr?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='pomospective'&gt;POMOSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to schedule also non-billable time, something I need to do before working on Pomodori needs to run on Pomodoro too, even though is not tracked here.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Few pomodoros are always good pomodoros.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  109|\@spike trying semr. I need to remove the oniguruma dependency if I want to use it. It looks possible. Doing.|2009-03-26 17:31:06 -0500
  110|\@spike semr: wrote to the author. I can't make it work with plain regexp. Ready to go manual html parsing.|2009-03-26 18:10:27 -0500
  111|\@spike own solution with replacement done by just expanding HTML into the template. Working.|2009-03-26 18:43:07 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>extracting controllers</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/24/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/24/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_9'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modularization manual acceptance UI plus fixing button actions plus add test coverage 4 =&amp;gt; 4&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization move models to models and controllers to controllers plus renaming 2 =&amp;gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was able to close with the main refactoring operations like extracting controllers and fix the test suite&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I started manual acceptance of the new GUI and there are button actions to fix&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Today: keep going with the manual acceptance until everything works and create test to cover the fix, commit a working app.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Final refactoring: rename countdown field, move pomodoro to models, delete useless old wrapper UI classes and commit again&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Everything should be ready for the next session to start working again on charts.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Be careful with breaks and longer breaks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='pomospective'&gt;POMOSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had session abort 2 hours before expected. Nothing I can do about it right now.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I was good with estimates to close the refactoring&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I was strict with 5 mins break: did nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several quick IM message exchange&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Abort session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  103
  |@modularization fixed void click with a sender argument, now fixing submit click and writing tests
  |2009-03-24 08:03:15 -0500
  104
  |@modularization realized I was not saving the pomo on submit fixed
  |2009-03-24 08:35:10 -0500
  105
  |@modularization cosmetic changes to summary position plus tried borderless
  |2009-03-24 09:06:44 -0500
  106
  |@modularization committed, plus some other small fixes like removing the application class that was almost useless
  |2009-03-24 09:38:46 -0500
  107
  |@modularization renamed and moved the countdown field into timer controller
  |2009-03-24 11:20:35:43 -0500
  108
  |@modularization moved controllers and models to specific folders, fixed slow tests by mocking main view
  |2009-03-24 11:58:18:26 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>closing huge refactoring (hopefully)</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/23/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/23/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_6'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done_6'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modularization modal button controller with on click methods for submit, void, stop and callbacks to main view to change labels 4 =&amp;gt; 5&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization summary controller to control statistics display with update-summary and format-metrics 2 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was taking a convolute path when I saw a state machine in the modal button controller. That&amp;#8217;s BDUF and not the simplest thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='pomospective'&gt;POMOSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forced to abort current pomodoro and session for external problems.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Forcing brain relaxing activities during the break. No more mails/rss, plus standup from chair.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Going easy on long break to avoid brain draining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  97|@modalcontroller creating necessary action behavior when pressing the button with different states|2009-03-23 16:55:58 -0500
  98|@modalcontroller I think I'm done with the controller, now need to install it into the main view.|2009-03-23 17:26:26 -0500
  99|@modalcontroller going through all the failing tests and organizing the test suite after the new test classes were added|2009-03-23 17:57:18 -0500
  100|@modalcontroller wasted some time for a stupid error (action instead of on-action)|2009-03-23 18:29:28 -0500
  101|@modalcontroller I fixed all tests, now I want to try a run before the refactoring that changes names and move models/controllers|2009-03-23 19:01:14 -0500
  102|@modularization it's almost working as before. I should be able to make it work 100% with just a couple of tweaks|2009-03-23 19:32:25 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>controllers refactoring</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/20/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/20/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_9'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done_5'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization migrate on-pomodoro-done and on-break-done and on-app-start to the countdown-field soon to be timer-controller and update test suite for it 4 =&amp;gt; 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modularization summary controller to control statistics display with update-summary and format-metrics 2&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization modal button controller with on click methods for submit, void, stop and callbacks to main view to change labels 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was able to split the refactoring operations into multiple tasks and that worked out very well.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I moved 90% of the timer logic out of application.rb into the timer-controller&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I had to move also the enabling/disabling logic out of the text field class&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I still need to extract the on-break-down method&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Today I&amp;#8217;ll try to close the timer controller (the renaming is basically the final action)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Then I want to extract the other logics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='retrospective'&gt;RETROSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was slower because I mixed two different tasks: extracting timer controller logic and creating a main view in parallel. I should have extracted the controller logic from application.rb leaving all the rest and then extracting or renaming application.rb to mainview. Remember next time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session aborted to go home fix Palomino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  92|@planning planned the day|2009-03-20 13:08:15 -0500
  93|@timercontroller created on break done logic|2009-03-20 13:38:49 -0500
  94|@modularization done with the timer controller logic. Now back to main view and application to integrate the work done with the goal of commit ASAP|2009-03-20 14:09:28 -0500
  95|@modalcontroller started implementing onclicks and title for modal button in related controller.|2009-03-20 14:40:38 -0500
  96|@modalcontroller created the modal controller and thinking that shoul only contain a state machine|2009-03-20 15:11:40 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>extracting controllers</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/19/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/19/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_6__5'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 6 =&amp;gt; 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done_5'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization take some time to understand how much work still to be done and fill a task list to close in 6 pomodoros 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization migrate on-pomodoro-done and on-break-done and on-app-start to the countdown-field soon to be timer-controller and update test suite for it 1 =&amp;gt; 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modularization summary controller to control statistics display with update-summary and format-metrics 2&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization modal button controller with on click methods for submit, void, stop and callbacks to main view to change labels 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started to see the light of the refactoring but I still have an hard time figuring out how much work is to be done.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I should be done next session in another 8 pomodoros.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='retrospective'&gt;RETROSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planned 6, actually done 5&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I split the modularization into multiple tasks and that worked. Underestimated heavily the timer controller work.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I was fast and fairly focused&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A couple of internal interruptions completely avoidable. Close chat next time, let people use the phone (somehow they need more effort to call)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the clean code cheat sheet while reading the last agile in a flash card. I should have deferred this to the to-do list. The error is always the same: thinking I can do something in the 5 mins break and it takes 15 mins instead. Defer, defer, defer.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Voided again, my bad. I couldn&amp;#8217;t resist to formulate a tweet after reading on twitter and it took ages. I should consider not opening twitters each break because potentially dangerous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palomino&amp;#8217;s updates from wife, aborting. Can&amp;#8217;t really close chat in this case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  87|@planning trying to shrink refactoring to 6 pomodoros today|2009-03-19 10:20:45 -0500
  88|@planning splitted tasks for the modularization process.|2009-03-19 11:03:02 -0500
  89|@modularization moving timer related event handling from application to timer controller.|2009-03-19 11:50:38 -0500
  90|@modularization going fast but much more than a single pomo to move all behavior into the timer controller.|2009-03-19 12:21:21 -0500
  91|@modularization last pomodoro of the day. I think I did big steps but underestimated the effort. Mostly done with the new timer controller.|2009-03-19 13:08:44 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>main view work in progress</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/17/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/17/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_9'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done_7'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;add gh-pages as submodule of master 2 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization: replace actual application.rb UI with mainview object 2 =&amp;gt; 3&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization: extract multiple controllers and new mainview object from application.rb. 4 =&amp;gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modularization: extract multiple controllers and new mainview object from application.rb. 4 =&amp;gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to decide how big the refactoring should be and if I can call it refactoring or just a re-write of the application.rb&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I think UI modularization is more appropriate&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The work to do is to finish the layout of the mainview until I have more or less the same visual appeal of before&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Consider not to waste too much time fine tweaking the UI, try to get the modularization done first and then fine tweak the UI. The important thing is that you see everything on the UI working as before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='retrospective'&gt;RETROSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planned 9, actually done 7&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I have to be more careful about judging how much time I have available considering one long break every 4 hours&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The refactoring operations are much more complicated than expected I should split into multiple tasks or consider if I&amp;#8217;m working on focus. Is the main view creation part of the controller extraction?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  73|@planning plus fixing some markdown jekyll generation issue|2009-03-16 15:07:24 -0500
  74|@refactor creating the main view and learning how to align layout-views correctly using the example app|2009-03-16 15:37:57 -0500
  75|@refactor creating the main-view more layout madness|2009-03-16 16:08:50 -0500
  76|@refactor creating the main view. Had to decide if to use the same label for input and output. Also had a look at NSIMage for the pomo icon|2009-03-16 16:39:49 -0500
  77|@refactor done with main-view creation copy pasting from application. It doesn't visualize as expected.|2009-03-16 17:29:42 -0500
  78|@refactor testing the new main view but having problems to see where the margin of the layouts are.|2009-03-16 18:02:54 -0500
  79|@refactor did some progress on understanding layouts. The mode vertical/horizontal for example. Still fighting for the best layout.|2009-03-16 18:36:55 -0500
  80|@website finally got gh-pages as master submodule so I can change the site from the master branch|2009-03-17 08:43:32 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>some refactoring</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/16/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/16/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='today_planned_9'&gt;TODAY PLANNED 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;refact extract multiple controllers and new mainview object from application.rb 4&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;charts Add a feature to the pomodoro model so that &amp;#8216;something&amp;#8217; in the description is automatically collected as tag internally 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='today_done'&gt;TODAY DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='today_not_done'&gt;TODAY NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refact extract multiple controllers and new mainview object from application.rb. 4 =&amp;gt; 7&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;charts Add a feature to the pomodoro model so that &amp;#8216;something&amp;#8217; in the description is automatically collected as tag internally. 4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='relevant_history'&gt;RELEVANT HISTORY&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>work on charts started</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/13/charts.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/13/charts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just realized that this brain dump and retrospective I was writing at the end of each planning page for the day is a perfect fit for the content of this micro blog! The retrospective is process only: how my PT (Pomodoro Technique) is doing, pros and cons, what went right and what went wrong. The standup is to get started for the day: yesterday&amp;#8217;s achievements, today&amp;#8217;s plan, design ideas and so on. Everyday is taking me 1 pomodoro for this and definitely worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='retrospective'&gt;Retrospective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still shooting for half a day of work these days, that means around 8 pomodoros.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Productive morning no internal/external interruptions.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t forget about the longer break this time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;Standup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is now a button that opens a new window with a webview that shows just a static HTML. The next step is of course to connect that HTML generation to the pomodoro history.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I need a component that starting from a template is able to generate the HTML table with correct numbers to host the current pomodoros worked by tags chart.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I also started thinking about refactoring the appliction.rb main file into multiple controllers, one for each part of the UI.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I found the following architectural rule to be consistent: one class per view that represents only the UI tree and nothing else. One controller for each sub-view (this is because a sub-view is really an independent user story on its own). The controller can use zero or more model objects. There are controllers with no back end model. The controller works as a presenter: the controller knows about views and model and send command to change the view when the model change.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I tried choctop: it doesn&amp;#8217;t work without an underlying Xcode project, or at least not the tutorial. It&amp;#8217;s a framework, so I suppose it can be used also with macruby. But I don&amp;#8217;t know how and now it&amp;#8217;s too complex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
69|@planning realized I can use the blog feature of gh-pages as a daily plan page, retrospective and the rest.|2009-03-13 09:16:42 -0500
70|@mvp started refactoring by extracting void pomodoro function|2009-03-13 09:55:06 -0500
71|@refact extended pomodoro_controller to call the view and started a new main_view to remove everything UI related from application.rb|2009-03-13 11:03:19 -0500
72|@project migrated to 0.4 now playing again with view_layout expansion to remove abolute widgets locations.|2009-03-13 11:34:30 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>